[
    {
        "category": "Americanisms",
        "question": "Britains say 'tarmac'; Americans say ------.",
        "answer": "runway"
    },
    {
        "category": "Analogies",
        "question": "Analogy: 'Ancient' is to 'old' as 'recent' is to --------.",
        "answer": "current"
    },
    {
        "category": "Analogies",
        "question": "Bull - cow as fox - ----------.",
        "answer": "vixen"
    },
    {
        "category": "Analogies",
        "question": "Goose - geese as passerby - -----------.",
        "answer": "passersby"
    },
    {
        "category": "Anatomy",
        "question": "Your ---- holds your head to your shoulders.",
        "answer": "neck"
    },
    {
        "category": "Arts",
        "question": "In what field of study would you find \"flying buttresses\"?",
        "answer": "architecture"
    },
    {
        "category": "Arts",
        "question": "The study of building design is ------------.",
        "answer": "architecture"
    },
    {
        "category": "Arts",
        "question": "This statue was found on the Greek island of Melos in 1820.",
        "answer": "Venus de Milo"
    },
    {
        "category": "Arts",
        "question": "Three main types of Greek columns are Doric, Ionic, and ----------.",
        "answer": "Corinthian"
    },
    {
        "category": "Arts",
        "question": "What Dutch master painted 64 self-portraits?",
        "answer": "Rembrandt"
    },
    {
        "category": "Arts",
        "question": "Where is the Louvre located?",
        "answer": "Paris"
    },
    {
        "category": "Arts",
        "question": "Who painted the Mona Lisa?",
        "answer": "Leonardo da Vinci"
    },
    {
        "category": "Astrology",
        "question": "What is the only sign in the zodiac which doesn't represent a living thing?",
        "answer": "Libra"
    },
    {
        "category": "Astrology",
        "question": "Which month has a diamond as a birthstone?",
        "answer": "April"
    },
    {
        "category": "Astronomy",
        "question": "A heavenly body moving under the attraction of the Sun and consisting of a nucleus and a tail is a(n) -----.",
        "answer": "comet"
    },
    {
        "category": "Astronomy",
        "question": "Does Uranus have an aurora?",
        "answer": "yes"
    },
    {
        "category": "Astronomy",
        "question": "From 1979 until 2000 the most distant planet from the earth was -------.",
        "answer": "Neptune"
    },
    {
        "category": "Astronomy",
        "question": "How many planets are there in our solar system?",
        "answer": "nine"
    },
    {
        "category": "Astronomy",
        "question": "If you're in the northern hemisphere, Polaris, the North Star, can be found by looking which direction?",
        "answer": "north"
    },
    {
        "category": "Astronomy",
        "question": "Name the largest planet in the solar system.",
        "answer": "Jupiter"
    },
    {
        "category": "Astronomy",
        "question": "Name the second-largest planet in the solar system.",
        "answer": "saturn"
    },
    {
        "category": "Astronomy",
        "question": "Our galaxy is commonly known as the --------.",
        "answer": "Milky Way"
    },
    {
        "category": "Astronomy",
        "question": "The Big Dipper is part of what constellation?",
        "answer": "Ursa Major"
    },
    {
        "category": "Astronomy",
        "question": "The North Star is also known as -------.",
        "answer": "Polaris"
    },
    {
        "category": "Astronomy",
        "question": "The fourth planet from the sun is ----.",
        "answer": "Mars"
    },
    {
        "category": "Astronomy",
        "question": "The name for the group of stars which form a hunter with a club and shield is -----.",
        "answer": "Orion"
    },
    {
        "category": "Astronomy",
        "question": "The planet closest to the sun is -------.",
        "answer": "Mercury"
    },
    {
        "category": "Astronomy",
        "question": "The spiral galaxy nearest ours is the --------- galaxy.",
        "answer": "Andromeda"
    },
    {
        "category": "Astronomy",
        "question": "The tides on the earth's oceans are actually created by gravitational pull from the ----.",
        "answer": "Moon"
    },
    {
        "category": "Astronomy",
        "question": "This cluster of stars is also known as the Seven Sisters.",
        "answer": "Pleiades"
    },
    {
        "category": "Astronomy",
        "question": "This comet appears every 76.3 years.",
        "answer": "Comet Halley"
    },
    {
        "category": "Astronomy",
        "question": "This planet's diameter is most equal to that of the earth's.",
        "answer": "Venus"
    },
    {
        "category": "Astronomy",
        "question": "What does \"Ursa Major\" mean in everyday English?",
        "answer": "great bear"
    },
    {
        "category": "Astronomy",
        "question": "What is the astronomical name for a group of stars?",
        "answer": "constellation"
    },
    {
        "category": "Astronomy",
        "question": "What is the name for the theoretical end-product of the gravitational collapse of a massive star?",
        "answer": "black hole"
    },
    {
        "category": "Astronomy",
        "question": "What is the name used to describe the \"minor planets\"?",
        "answer": "asteroids"
    },
    {
        "category": "Astronomy",
        "question": "What is the ocean of air around the earth called?",
        "answer": "atmosphere"
    },
    {
        "category": "Astronomy",
        "question": "What is the proper name for falling stars?",
        "answer": "meteors"
    },
    {
        "category": "Astronomy",
        "question": "What is the term for the path followed a by a small body around a massive body in space?",
        "answer": "orbit"
    },
    {
        "category": "Astronomy",
        "question": "What phenomenon is caused by the gravitational attraction of the moon?",
        "answer": "tides"
    },
    {
        "category": "Astronomy",
        "question": "What planet boasts the Great Red Spot?",
        "answer": "Jupiter"
    },
    {
        "category": "Bet you don't know ;-)",
        "question": "The two sexes of humans are male and ------?",
        "answer": "female"
    },
    {
        "category": "Biochemistry",
        "question": "This poisonous, oily liquid occurs in tobacco leaves.",
        "answer": "nicotine"
    },
    {
        "category": "Biochemistry",
        "question": "This protein makes the blood red in color.",
        "answer": "Haemoglobin"
    },
    {
        "category": "Biology",
        "question": "Every human has one of these on their tummies.",
        "answer": "navel"
    },
    {
        "category": "Biology",
        "question": "How many large holes are in your head?",
        "answer": "seven"
    },
    {
        "category": "Biology",
        "question": "This complex substance makes up all living things.",
        "answer": "protoplasm"
    },
    {
        "category": "Biology",
        "question": "What is normal body temperature for an adult human (in degrees fahrenheit)?",
        "answer": "98.6"
    },
    {
        "category": "Botany",
        "question": "The practice of joining the parts of two plants to make them grow as one is called --------.",
        "answer": "grafting"
    },
    {
        "category": "Botany",
        "question": "These flowerless plants grow on bare rocks and tree stumps.",
        "answer": "lichen"
    },
    {
        "category": "Botany",
        "question": "This fruit has its seeds on the outside.",
        "answer": "strawberry"
    },
    {
        "category": "Botany",
        "question": "This term means 'cone-bearing trees'.",
        "answer": "conifers"
    },
    {
        "category": "Botany",
        "question": "What fruit bear the latin name \"citrus grandis\"?",
        "answer": "grapefruit"
    },
    {
        "category": "Calendar",
        "question": "How many days where there in 1976?",
        "answer": "three hundred and sixty six"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Alvin & Simon had a brother called ----.",
        "answer": "Theodore"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "An Andy Panda cartoon gave birth to a famous, cantankerous bird. Name him.",
        "answer": "Woody Woodpecker"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "An adventurous penguin named Tennessee Tuxedo had a sidekick named -------?",
        "answer": "Chumley"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "An alien creature in a funny hat has opposed both Bugs Bunny and Daffy Duck.  Where is he from?",
        "answer": "Mars"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Before Olive Oil met Popeye she was engaged to someone.  Who was he?",
        "answer": "Ham Gravy"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Benny and Cecil were at odds with whom?",
        "answer": "John"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Bugs always finds himself at the wrong end of a gun, usually toted by either Elmer Fudd or who?",
        "answer": "Yosemite Sam"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Casper the Friendly Ghost frolicked with which witch?",
        "answer": "Wendy"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Charles Boyer inspired a cartoon skunk. Who?",
        "answer": "Pepe le Pew"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Famous Phrases: Who knows? The ------.",
        "answer": "Shadow"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Gadzookie has a large, green friend. Who is he?",
        "answer": "Godzilla"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Hanna-Barbera rose to fame by creating what duo for MGM?",
        "answer": "Tom and Jerry"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "How does Wonder Woman control her invisible airplane?",
        "answer": "mental powers"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "In the cartoons who was Hokie Wolf's sidekick?",
        "answer": "Ding"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "In what city does Fat Albert live?",
        "answer": "Philadelphia"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Mentor of Titan had two children in the Marvel comics, Thanos and ---?",
        "answer": "Ero"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Miss Buckley is secretary to what commanding officer?",
        "answer": "General Halftrack"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Name Alley Oop's girl friend.",
        "answer": "Oola"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Name Cathy's on again/off again boy friend?",
        "answer": "Irving"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Name Dennis the Menace's next door neighbors.",
        "answer": "Mr and Mrs Wilson"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Name Donald Duck's girlfriend?",
        "answer": "Daisy"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Name Hagar the Horrible's dog.",
        "answer": "Snert"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Name Li'l Abner's favorite Indian drink.",
        "answer": "Kickapoo Joy Juice"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Name the European hit, now an animated series about underwater people.",
        "answer": "The Snorks"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Name the apartments the Jetson's live in.",
        "answer": "The Skypad Apartments"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Name the dog in the Yankee Doodle cartoons.",
        "answer": "Chopper"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Name the fastest mouse in all of Mexico.",
        "answer": "Speedy Gonzalez"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Name the ranger who was always after Yogi Bear.",
        "answer": "Rick"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Name the town that Fred, Wilma, Barney, and Betty lived in.",
        "answer": "Bedrock"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "On what T.V. show could Tom Terrific be found?",
        "answer": "Captain Kangaroo"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Popeye's chief adversary has two names, Bluto and ------?",
        "answer": "Brutus"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Porky Pig had a girlfriend named --------.",
        "answer": "Petunia"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Tess Trueheart married which plainclothes detective?",
        "answer": "Dick Tracy"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "What came out of Milton's head?",
        "answer": "steam"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "What character did Tex Avery first create upon arriving at MGM?",
        "answer": "Screwball Squirrel"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "What comic strip character is Beetle Bailey's sister?",
        "answer": "Lois (of Hi and Lois)"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "What did Dagwood give up to marry Blondie?",
        "answer": "A family inheritance"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "What did Peppermint Patty always call Charlie Brown?",
        "answer": "Chuck"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "What is Batman's butler Alfred's last name.",
        "answer": "Pennyworth"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "What is Blondie's maiden name?",
        "answer": "Oop"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "What is Dennis the Menace's last name?",
        "answer": "Mitchell"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "What is Smokey Stover's job?",
        "answer": "fireman"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "What is Super Chicken's partners name?",
        "answer": "Fred"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "What is the mother's name in Family Circus?",
        "answer": "Thelma"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "What is the name of Duddley Do-Right's horse?",
        "answer": "Horse"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "What is the name of the Family Circus's dog?",
        "answer": "Barf"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "What kind of dog is Scooby Doo?",
        "answer": "great dane"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "What type of plant does Broom Hilda sell?",
        "answer": "venus flytrap"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "What was Daffy Duck's favorite insult?",
        "answer": "You're dispicable!"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "What was George of the Jungle always running in to?",
        "answer": "A tree"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "What was the first cartoon to feature sound?",
        "answer": "Steamboat Willie"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "What was the name of George of the Jungle's pet elephant?",
        "answer": "Shep"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "What was the name of Speed Racer's car?",
        "answer": "The Mach Five"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "What was the original name Charles Schultz had for Peanuts?",
        "answer": "Li'l Folks"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "What was the relationship between Superman and Supergirl?",
        "answer": "cousin"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "When Tweety exclaimed, \"I thought I saw a putty tat!\", who did he see?",
        "answer": "Sylvester"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "When danger appeared, Quick Draw McGraw became which super hero?",
        "answer": "El KaBong"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "When not a Birdman, what does Ray Randall do for a living?",
        "answer": "police officer"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "When not fighting crime, what did Underdog do for a living?",
        "answer": "shoeshine boy"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Where are Rocket J. Squirel and Bullwinkle Moose from?",
        "answer": "Frostbite Falls"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Where did Clark Kent attend college?",
        "answer": "Metropolis University"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Where did George of the Jungle live?",
        "answer": "Imgwee Gwee Valley"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Where did Mighty Mouse get his superpowers?",
        "answer": "supermarket"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Where do Rocky and Bullwinkle play football?",
        "answer": "What'samatta University"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Where does George Jetson work?",
        "answer": "Spacely Sprockets"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Where does Yogi Bear Live?",
        "answer": "Jellystone Park"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Which comic strip was banned from \"Stars and Stripes\"?",
        "answer": "Beetle Bailey"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Which superhero loves peace enough to kill for it?",
        "answer": "Peacemaker"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Who always tried to kill Krazy Kat?",
        "answer": "Captain Marvel"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Who is Donald Duck's uncle?",
        "answer": "Scrooge"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Who is Sally Brown's sweet baboo?",
        "answer": "Linus"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Who is Scooby Doo's nephew??",
        "answer": "Scrappy Doo"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Who is Snoopy's arch enemy?",
        "answer": "The Red Baron"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Who is stationed at Camp Swampy in the comic strips?",
        "answer": "Beetle Bailey"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Who runs Andy Capp's favorite pub?",
        "answer": "Jack and Jill"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Who says, \"Th-th-th-that's all folks!\"",
        "answer": "Porky Pig"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Who shot Bruce Wayne's parents?",
        "answer": "Chill"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Who was Dick Dastardly's pet?",
        "answer": "Muttley"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Who was always trying to get rent from Andy Capp?",
        "answer": "Percy"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Who was the Hulk's first friend?",
        "answer": "Rick Jones"
    },
    {
        "category": "Cartoon Trivia",
        "question": "Who was the original voice of Mickey Mouse?",
        "answer": "Walt Disney"
    },
    {
        "category": "Chemistry",
        "question": "Hydrogen Hydroxide is more commonly known as what?",
        "answer": "water"
    },
    {
        "category": "Chemistry",
        "question": "Nitrogen, a poisonous gas, makes up 78% of the --- that we breathe.",
        "answer": "air"
    },
    {
        "category": "Chemistry",
        "question": "Sodium Hydroxide is more commonly known as ---.",
        "answer": "lye"
    },
    {
        "category": "Chemistry",
        "question": "Sodium bicarbonate is better known as ---------.",
        "answer": "baking soda"
    },
    {
        "category": "Chemistry",
        "question": "The process of removing salt from sea water is known as -----------.",
        "answer": "desalination"
    },
    {
        "category": "Chemistry",
        "question": "The smallest portion of a substance capable of existing independently and retaining its original properties is a(n) --------.",
        "answer": "molecule"
    },
    {
        "category": "Chemistry",
        "question": "This ancient attempt to transmute base metals into gold was called -------.",
        "answer": "alchemy"
    },
    {
        "category": "Chemistry",
        "question": "This is the heaviest naturally occurring element.",
        "answer": "uranium"
    },
    {
        "category": "Chemistry",
        "question": "This is the symbol for tin.",
        "answer": "Sn"
    },
    {
        "category": "Chemistry",
        "question": "This poisonous gas is in the exhaust fumes from cars.",
        "answer": "carbon monoxide"
    },
    {
        "category": "Chemistry",
        "question": "Water containing carbon dioxide under pressure is called ---- -----.",
        "answer": "soda water"
    },
    {
        "category": "Chemistry",
        "question": "What is it that turns blue litmus paper red?",
        "answer": "acid"
    },
    {
        "category": "Chemistry",
        "question": "What is the abbreviation for trinitrotoluene?",
        "answer": "TNT"
    },
    {
        "category": "Chemistry",
        "question": "What is the chemical symbol for copper?",
        "answer": "Cu"
    },
    {
        "category": "Chemistry",
        "question": "What is the chemical symbol for gold?",
        "answer": "Au"
    },
    {
        "category": "Chemistry",
        "question": "What is the main component of air?",
        "answer": "nitrogen"
    },
    {
        "category": "Chemistry",
        "question": "What is the more scientific name for quicksilver?",
        "answer": "mercury"
    },
    {
        "category": "Chemistry",
        "question": "What is the symbol for iron in chemistry?",
        "answer": "Fe"
    },
    {
        "category": "Chemistry",
        "question": "What is the symbol for silver?",
        "answer": "Ag"
    },
    {
        "category": "Christmas",
        "question": "Name the loner rebel reindeer with the red shiny nose.",
        "answer": "Rudolph"
    },
    {
        "category": "Christmas",
        "question": "Santa Claus reportedly lives at the ----- Pole.",
        "answer": "north"
    },
    {
        "category": "Comic Strip Trivia",
        "question": "What comic strip is set at Camp Swampy?",
        "answer": "Beetle Bailey"
    },
    {
        "category": "Computer Science",
        "question": "That big square thing you're staring at right now is called a -------?",
        "answer": "monitor"
    },
    {
        "category": "Computer Science",
        "question": "The Internet Relay Chat Program, which normally connects to port 6667, is more commonly known as ---.",
        "answer": "IRC"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "--isms:  Exalting one's country above all others.",
        "answer": "nationalism"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "--isms:  The belief that there is no God.",
        "answer": "atheism"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "--isms:  The theory that man cannot prove the existence of a god.",
        "answer": "agnosticism"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "-ism: The belief in the existence of a god or gods.",
        "answer": "theism"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "-isms: A diseased condition resulting from the use of beverages such as whiskey.",
        "answer": "alcoholism"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "-isms: A one-party system of government in which control is maintained by force and regimentation.",
        "answer": "fascism"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "-isms: A painful stiffness of the muscles and joints",
        "answer": "rheumatism"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "-isms: A severe or unfavorable judgment.",
        "answer": "criticism"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "-isms: An economic system characterized by private ownership and competition.",
        "answer": "capitalism"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "-isms: Excessive emphasis on financial gain.",
        "answer": "commercialism"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "-isms: Excessive enthusiasm or zeal for a cause.",
        "answer": "fanaticism"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "-isms: Poisoning caused by a toxin in improperly prepared food.",
        "answer": "botulism"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "-isms: Public ownership of the basic means of production, distribution, and exchange.",
        "answer": "socialism"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "-isms: The belief in living a very austere and self-denying life.",
        "answer": "asceticism"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "A clip, shaped like a bar to keep a woman's hair in place is a -------.",
        "answer": "barrette"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "A depilatory is a substance used for removing ----.",
        "answer": "hair"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "A device used to change the voltage of alternating currents is a ----------.",
        "answer": "transformer"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "A flat, round hat sometimes worn by soldiers is a -----.",
        "answer": "beret"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "A government in which power is restricted to a few is a(n) ----------.",
        "answer": "oligarchy"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "A person in his eighties is called a(n) ------------.",
        "answer": "octogenarian"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "A person who starts fires maliciously is a(n) ---------.",
        "answer": "arsonist"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "A person with a strong desire to steal is a(n) --------.",
        "answer": "kleptomaniac"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "A pugilist is a -----.",
        "answer": "boxer"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "A receptacle for holy water is a(n) ----.",
        "answer": "font"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "A sun-dried grape is known as a(n) ------.",
        "answer": "raisin"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "A word like 'NASA' formed from the initials of other words is a(n) ------.",
        "answer": "acronym"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "Acrophobia is a fear of -------.",
        "answer": "heights"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "An \"omniscient\" person has unlimited ----------.",
        "answer": "knowledge"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "An anemometer measures ---- --------.",
        "answer": "wind velocity"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "An animal stuffer is a(n) -----------.",
        "answer": "taxidermist"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "An artist supports his canvas on a(n) -----.",
        "answer": "easel"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "An instrument on a car to measure the distance travelled is called a(n) --------.",
        "answer": "odometer"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "Androphobia is the fear of -----.",
        "answer": "males"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "Animals that once existed but don't exist now are said to be -------.",
        "answer": "extinct"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "Any object worn as a charm may be called a(n) ------.",
        "answer": "amulet"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "Bibliophobia is a fear of -----.",
        "answer": "books"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "Brontophobia is the fear of -------.",
        "answer": "thunder"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "Dendrochronology is better known as ----------.",
        "answer": "ring dating"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "Doraphobia is the fear of ---------.",
        "answer": "fur"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "Eleutherophobia is a fear of -------.",
        "answer": "freedom"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "Gymnophobia is the fear of ----------.",
        "answer": "naked bodies"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "Hills and ridges composed of drifting sand are known as -----.",
        "answer": "dunes"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "Ichthyology is the study of --------.",
        "answer": "fish"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "Legal Terms: A crime more serious than a misdemeanor.",
        "answer": "felony"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "Legal Terms: A formal agreement enforceable by law.",
        "answer": "contract"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "Legal Terms: A supplement to a will.",
        "answer": "codicil"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "Legal Terms: The people chosen to render a verdict in a court.",
        "answer": "jury"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "Legal Terms: To steal property entrusted to one's care.",
        "answer": "embezzle"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "Name the pain-inflicting person you go to to get your teeth fixed.",
        "answer": "dentist"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "Name the porceilan chair you sit on at least once a day.",
        "answer": "toilet"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "One who tells fortunes by the stars is a(n) ----------.",
        "answer": "astrologer"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "Rats, mice, beavers, and squirrels are all -------.",
        "answer": "rodents"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "The art of tracing designs and taking impressions of them is -----------.",
        "answer": "lithography"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "The covering on the tip of a shoelace is a(n) -----.",
        "answer": "aglet"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "The distance around the outside of a circle is its ------------.",
        "answer": "circumference"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "The earth's atmosphere and the space beyond is known as ---------.",
        "answer": "aerospace"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "The effect produced when sound is reflected back is known as a(n) ----.",
        "answer": "echo"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "The feeling of having experienced something before is known as -------.",
        "answer": "deja vu"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "The science of preparing and dispensing drugs is --------.",
        "answer": "pharmacy"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "The science of providing men, equipment and supplies for military operations is called --------.",
        "answer": "logistics"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "The study of human behaviour is ----------.",
        "answer": "psychology"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "The study of human pre-history is -----------.",
        "answer": "archaeology"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "The study of insects is ----------.",
        "answer": "entomology"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "The study of light and its relation to sight is called ------.",
        "answer": "optics"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "The study of man and culture is known as ----------.",
        "answer": "anthropology"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "The study of natural phenomena: motion, forces, light, sound, etc. is called ------.",
        "answer": "physics"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "The study of plants is ------.",
        "answer": "botany"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "The study of religion is --------.",
        "answer": "theology"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "The study of sound is ---------.",
        "answer": "acoustics"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "The study of the composition of substances and the changes that they undergo is ---------.",
        "answer": "chemistry"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "The study of the earth's physical divisions into mountains, seas, etc. is ---------.",
        "answer": "geography"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "The study of the manner in which organisms carry on their life processes is ---------.",
        "answer": "physiology"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "The symbols used on a map are explained by the ------.",
        "answer": "legend"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "The treatment of disease by chemical substances which are toxic to the causative micro-organisms is called ------------.",
        "answer": "chemotherapy"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "The weight at the end of a pendulum is a(n) ------.",
        "answer": "bob"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "The wide wall built along the banks of rivers to stop flooding is a(n) -----.",
        "answer": "levee"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "The word \"cumulus\" refers to a type of -----------.",
        "answer": "cloud"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "This instrument is used for measuring the distance between two points, on a curved surface.",
        "answer": "calliper"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "This instrument measures atmospheric pressure.",
        "answer": "barometer"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "This instrument measures the velocity of the wind.",
        "answer": "anemometer"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "This is the fear of enclosed spaces.",
        "answer": "claustrophobia"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "This word is used as the international radio distress call.",
        "answer": "mayday"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "This word means \"split personality\".",
        "answer": "schizophrenia"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "Throat, foxing, and platform are parts of a(n) --------.",
        "answer": "shoe"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "Toxiphobia is a fear of ---------.",
        "answer": "poison"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "What does a brandophile collect?",
        "answer": "cigar bands"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "What does a heliologist study?",
        "answer": "the sun"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "What does an ornithologist study?",
        "answer": "birds"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "What is a device to stem the flow of blood called?",
        "answer": "tourniquet"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "What is a dried plum called?",
        "answer": "prune"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "What is a female swan called?",
        "answer": "pen"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "What is a figure with eight equal sides called?",
        "answer": "octagon"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "What is another name for a tombstone inscription?",
        "answer": "epitaph"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "What is measured by a chronometer?",
        "answer": "time"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "What is the common name for a Japanese dwarf tree?",
        "answer": "bonsai"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "What is the common name for the Aurora Borealis?",
        "answer": "northern lights"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "What is the common term for a \"somnambulist\"?",
        "answer": "sleepwalker"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "What is the name for a branch of a river?",
        "answer": "tributary"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "What is the study of heredity called?",
        "answer": "genetics"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "What is the study of prehistoric plants and animals called?",
        "answer": "paleontology"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "What is the term for a castrated rooster?",
        "answer": "capon"
    },
    {
        "category": "Definitions",
        "question": "Which science studies weather?",
        "answer": "meteorology"
    },
    {
        "category": "Domestic Metallurgy",
        "question": "Name the clothing wrinkle remover that sounds like a kind of metal.",
        "answer": "iron"
    },
    {
        "category": "Don't Strain Yourself Thinking ;-)",
        "question": "A 3 1/2\" floppy disk measures --- and 1/2 inches across.",
        "answer": "3"
    },
    {
        "category": "Don't Strain Yourself Thinking ;-)",
        "question": "A brown crayon is what color?",
        "answer": "brown"
    },
    {
        "category": "Don't Strain Yourself Thinking ;-)",
        "question": "A smoke detector will alarm if it detects -----.",
        "answer": "smoke"
    },
    {
        "category": "Don't Strain Yourself Thinking ;-)",
        "question": "A water heater keeps ----- warm for you.",
        "answer": "water"
    },
    {
        "category": "Don't Strain Yourself Thinking ;-)",
        "question": "Although not all come from France, ------ fries are often served with hamburgers.",
        "answer": "french"
    },
    {
        "category": "Don't Strain Yourself Thinking ;-)",
        "question": "An ----- clock usually wakes you in the morning.",
        "answer": "alarm"
    },
    {
        "category": "Don't Strain Yourself Thinking ;-)",
        "question": "During the American Revolution, the Boston Tea Party took place in ------ Harbor.",
        "answer": "boston"
    },
    {
        "category": "Don't Strain Yourself Thinking ;-)",
        "question": "How do you spell abbreviation?",
        "answer": "abbreviation"
    },
    {
        "category": "Don't Strain Yourself Thinking ;-)",
        "question": "How many pencils are there in a dozen?",
        "answer": "twelve"
    },
    {
        "category": "Drama",
        "question": "\"Our Town\" is a play by whom?",
        "answer": "Thornton Wilder"
    },
    {
        "category": "Drama",
        "question": "The play \"Our Town\" is set where?",
        "answer": "Grover's Corners"
    },
    {
        "category": "Fantasy",
        "question": "What is a sorcerer who deals in black magic called?",
        "answer": "necromancer"
    },
    {
        "category": "Food",
        "question": "Boston butt, jowl, and picnic ham are parts of a ------.",
        "answer": "pig"
    },
    {
        "category": "Food and Drink",
        "question": "Even though it tastes nothing like grapes, a ---------- is often eaten for breakfast.",
        "answer": "grapefruit"
    },
    {
        "category": "Food and Drink",
        "question": "From what animal do we get venison?",
        "answer": "deer"
    },
    {
        "category": "Food and Drink",
        "question": "From which fish is caviar obtained?",
        "answer": "sturgeon"
    },
    {
        "category": "Food and Drink",
        "question": "From which fruit is the liqueur Kirsh made?",
        "answer": "cherry"
    },
    {
        "category": "Food and Drink",
        "question": "Iceberg, Boston, and Bibb are types of ---------.",
        "answer": "lettuce"
    },
    {
        "category": "Food and Drink",
        "question": "Laetrile is associated with the pit of which fruit?",
        "answer": "apricot"
    },
    {
        "category": "Food and Drink",
        "question": "Little round chocolate candies are known as _&m's.",
        "answer": "m"
    },
    {
        "category": "Food and Drink",
        "question": "Mustard, ketchup and onions on a hotdog are all ----------.",
        "answer": "condiments"
    },
    {
        "category": "Food and Drink",
        "question": "Name the only fruit named for its color.",
        "answer": "orange"
    },
    {
        "category": "Food and Drink",
        "question": "Natural vanilla flavoring comes from this plant.",
        "answer": "orchid"
    },
    {
        "category": "Food and Drink",
        "question": "Often drunk, this liquid is normally harvested from female cows.",
        "answer": "milk"
    },
    {
        "category": "Food and Drink",
        "question": "Often eaten for breakfast, bacon is actually the flesh of what barnyard animal?",
        "answer": "pig"
    },
    {
        "category": "Food and Drink",
        "question": "Often eaten for breakfast, the egg comes from what barnyard animal?",
        "answer": "chicken"
    },
    {
        "category": "Food and Drink",
        "question": "Rum is made from this plant.",
        "answer": "sugar cane"
    },
    {
        "category": "Food and Drink",
        "question": "Vermicelli literally means -----------.",
        "answer": "little worms"
    },
    {
        "category": "Food and Drink",
        "question": "What do you get when you add fresh fruit to red wine?",
        "answer": "sangria"
    },
    {
        "category": "Food and Drink",
        "question": "What is Japanese \"sake\" made from?",
        "answer": "rice"
    },
    {
        "category": "Food and Drink",
        "question": "What is the name of the syrup drained from raw sugar?",
        "answer": "molasses"
    },
    {
        "category": "Food and Drink",
        "question": "What kind of nuts are used in marzipan?",
        "answer": "almonds"
    },
    {
        "category": "Food and Drink",
        "question": "Where is the best brandy bottled?",
        "answer": "cognac"
    },
    {
        "category": "Food and Drink",
        "question": "Where was Budweiser first brewed?",
        "answer": "St. Louis"
    },
    {
        "category": "Fun",
        "question": "Cocktails: Bourbon, sugar and mint make a(n) -----------.",
        "answer": "mint julep"
    },
    {
        "category": "Fun",
        "question": "Cocktails: Cognac (brandy) and white creme de menthe make a(n) -------------.",
        "answer": "stinger"
    },
    {
        "category": "Fun",
        "question": "Cocktails: Creme de Cacao, cream, and brandy make a(n) ----------.",
        "answer": "brandy alexander"
    },
    {
        "category": "Fun",
        "question": "Cocktails: Gin and Collins mix make a(n) ----------.",
        "answer": "Tom Collins"
    },
    {
        "category": "Fun",
        "question": "Cocktails: Rum, lime, and cola drink make a(n) ------------.",
        "answer": "cuba libre"
    },
    {
        "category": "Fun",
        "question": "Cocktails: Triple sec, tequila, and lemon or lime juice make a(n) ---------.",
        "answer": "margarita"
    },
    {
        "category": "Fun",
        "question": "Cocktails: Vodka and Kahlua make a -----------.",
        "answer": "black russian"
    },
    {
        "category": "Fun",
        "question": "Cocktails: Vodka, orange juice and Galliano make a(n) -----------.",
        "answer": "Harvey Wallbanger"
    },
    {
        "category": "Fun",
        "question": "Cocktails: Whiskey, hot coffee, and whipped cream make a(n) ---------.",
        "answer": "Irish coffee"
    },
    {
        "category": "Games",
        "question": "A bridge hand with no cards in one suit is said to have a -------.",
        "answer": "void"
    },
    {
        "category": "Games",
        "question": "A poker hand consisting of three of a kind and a pair is called a -------.",
        "answer": "full house"
    },
    {
        "category": "Games",
        "question": "How many balls are used in a game of snooker including the cue ball?",
        "answer": "twenty two"
    },
    {
        "category": "Games",
        "question": "How many dots are there on a pair of dice?",
        "answer": "forty two"
    },
    {
        "category": "Games",
        "question": "How many squares are there on a chessboard?",
        "answer": "sixty four"
    },
    {
        "category": "Games",
        "question": "If you \"peg out\" what game are you playing?",
        "answer": "cribbage"
    },
    {
        "category": "Games",
        "question": "In poker five cards of the same suit is called a(n) --------.",
        "answer": "flush"
    },
    {
        "category": "Games",
        "question": "In pool, what color is the eight ball?",
        "answer": "black"
    },
    {
        "category": "Games",
        "question": "In which game might a person have a \"full house\"?",
        "answer": "poker"
    },
    {
        "category": "Games",
        "question": "In which game or sport are \"Staunton\" pieces used?",
        "answer": "chess"
    },
    {
        "category": "Games",
        "question": "In which game or sport can a person be \"skunked\"?",
        "answer": "cribbage"
    },
    {
        "category": "Games",
        "question": "In which sport are terms \"spare\" and \"gutter\" used?",
        "answer": "tenpin bowling"
    },
    {
        "category": "Games",
        "question": "In which sport or game are the terms: 'pin', 'fork', and 'skewer' used?",
        "answer": "chess"
    },
    {
        "category": "Games",
        "question": "In which sport or game is the term \"rook\" used?",
        "answer": "chess"
    },
    {
        "category": "Games",
        "question": "Name the only flexible murder weapon in the game of \"Cluedo\".",
        "answer": "rope"
    },
    {
        "category": "Games",
        "question": "Name the only woman suspect in the game of \"Cluedo\" who isn't married.",
        "answer": "Miss Scarlett"
    },
    {
        "category": "Games",
        "question": "These are the two highest valued letters in \"Scrabble\".  \"Q\" and -----.",
        "answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "category": "Games",
        "question": "This ancient Chinese game is played with 156 small rectangular tiles.",
        "answer": "mah jongg"
    },
    {
        "category": "Games",
        "question": "This is the lowest ranking suit in Bridge.",
        "answer": "clubs"
    },
    {
        "category": "Games",
        "question": "This term denotes a chess move in which both the king and the rook are moved.",
        "answer": "castling"
    },
    {
        "category": "Games",
        "question": "What bowling term means three straight strikes?",
        "answer": "turkey"
    },
    {
        "category": "Games",
        "question": "What game or sport is Bobby Fischer identified with?",
        "answer": "chess"
    },
    {
        "category": "Games",
        "question": "What number is on the opposite side of the \"five\" on dice?",
        "answer": "two"
    },
    {
        "category": "Games",
        "question": "What score is not possible for a cribbage hand?",
        "answer": "nineteen"
    },
    {
        "category": "Games",
        "question": "Which chess piece is usually valued as 5 points?",
        "answer": "rook"
    },
    {
        "category": "Games",
        "question": "Which game usually begins with, \"Is it animal, vegetable, or mineral?\"",
        "answer": "twenty questions"
    },
    {
        "category": "General Knowledge",
        "question": "Although it doesn't sound like a dog, ----dust is ornamental wood chips often placed in flowerbeds.",
        "answer": "bark"
    },
    {
        "category": "General Knowledge",
        "question": "Chicago Transit Authority is now known as which group?",
        "answer": "Chicago"
    },
    {
        "category": "General Knowledge",
        "question": "If you drive on a parkway, you park on a -------?",
        "answer": "driveway"
    },
    {
        "category": "General Knowledge",
        "question": "To refuel your car you go to a ----- station.",
        "answer": "petrol"
    },
    {
        "category": "General Knowledge",
        "question": "Wedding rings are normally worn on what finger of your hand?",
        "answer": "ring finger"
    },
    {
        "category": "General Knowledge",
        "question": "What are catalogued under the Dewey decimal system?",
        "answer": "books"
    },
    {
        "category": "General Knowledge",
        "question": "What are the 3 big colleges of the Ivy League? (name them alphabetically)",
        "answer": "Harvard, Princeton, Yale"
    },
    {
        "category": "General Knowledge",
        "question": "What company makes Pampers disposable diapers?",
        "answer": "Proctor & Gamble"
    },
    {
        "category": "General Knowledge",
        "question": "What do the initials U.F.O stand for?",
        "answer": "Unidentified Flying Object"
    },
    {
        "category": "General Knowledge",
        "question": "What do the letters in SAM missiles refer to?",
        "answer": "Surface-to-Air Missile"
    },
    {
        "category": "General Knowledge",
        "question": "What does IRS stand for?",
        "answer": "Internal Revenue Service"
    },
    {
        "category": "General Knowledge",
        "question": "What does a compass needle point to?",
        "answer": "north"
    },
    {
        "category": "General Knowledge",
        "question": "What does the abbreviation a.m. stand for?",
        "answer": "Ante Meridian"
    },
    {
        "category": "General Knowledge",
        "question": "What does the acronym CIA stand for?",
        "answer": "Central Intelligence Agency"
    },
    {
        "category": "General Knowledge",
        "question": "What is the minimum IQ score for the genius category?",
        "answer": "one hundred and forty"
    },
    {
        "category": "General Knowledge",
        "question": "What is this sign called \"&\"?",
        "answer": "ampersand"
    },
    {
        "category": "General Knowledge",
        "question": "When using a telephone, you must wait for a ---- tone before starting your call.",
        "answer": "dial"
    },
    {
        "category": "General Knowledge",
        "question": "Which U.S. president is on the five-dollar bill?",
        "answer": "Abraham Lincoln"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Acadia was the original name of which Canadian province?",
        "answer": "Nova Scotia"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Bridgeport is the largest city in which state?",
        "answer": "Connecticut"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Bridgetown is the capital of --------.",
        "answer": "Barbados"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Brussels is the capital of which country?",
        "answer": "Belgium"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Frankfort is the capital of which state?",
        "answer": "Kentucky"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Guayaquil is the largest city in what country?",
        "answer": "Ecuador"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Halifax is the capital of which Canadian province?",
        "answer": "Nova Scotia"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Havana is the capital of which country?",
        "answer": "Cuba"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "He invented the most common projection for world maps.",
        "answer": "Gerardus Mercator"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "He visited Australia and New Zealand, then surveyed the Pacific Coast of North America.",
        "answer": "Vancouver"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "How many stars are on the flag of New Zealand?",
        "answer": "four"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "If its 4:00pm in Seattle, Washington what time is it in Portland, Oregon?",
        "answer": "4:00pm"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In what city are the famous Tivoli Gardens?",
        "answer": "Copenhagen"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In what city is the Leaning Tower?",
        "answer": "Pisa"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In what city is the Smithsonian Institute?",
        "answer": "Washington"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In what country is Banff National Park?",
        "answer": "Canada"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In what country is Lahore?",
        "answer": "Pakistan"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In what country is Mandalay?",
        "answer": "Myanmar (formerly known as Burma)"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In what country is Taipei?",
        "answer": "Taiwan"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In what country is Thunder Bay?",
        "answer": "Canada"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In what country is the Jutland peninsula?",
        "answer": "Denmark"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In what country is the Mekong River Delta?",
        "answer": "Vietnam"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In what country is the Waterloo battlefield?",
        "answer": "Belgium"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In what country is the highest point in South America?",
        "answer": "Argentina"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In what country is the lowest point in South America?",
        "answer": "Argentina"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In what country is the source of the Blue Nile?",
        "answer": "Ethiopia"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In what island group is Corregidor?",
        "answer": "Philippines"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In what mountain range is Kicking Horse Pass?",
        "answer": "Rocky"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In what state is Concord?",
        "answer": "New Hampshire"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In which city is Red Square?",
        "answer": "Moscow"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In which city is Saint Paul's Cathedral?",
        "answer": "London"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In which city is Wembley Stadium?",
        "answer": "London"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In which city is the Bridge of Sighs?",
        "answer": "Venice"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In which city is the C.N. Tower?",
        "answer": "Toronto"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In which city is the Canale Grande?",
        "answer": "Venice"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In which city is the Colliseum located?",
        "answer": "Rome"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In which city is the Wailing Wall?",
        "answer": "Jerusalem"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In which country is Angel Falls?",
        "answer": "Venezuela"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In which country is Brest? (NOT Breast!)",
        "answer": "France"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In which country is Chennai (formerly Madras)?",
        "answer": "India"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In which country is Cusco?",
        "answer": "Peru"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In which country is Loch Ness?",
        "answer": "Scotland"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In which country is Normandy?",
        "answer": "France"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In which country is Sapporo?",
        "answer": "Japan"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In which country is the Calabria region?",
        "answer": "Italy"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In which country is the Dalai Lama's palace?",
        "answer": "Tibet"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In which country is the Great Victoria Desert?",
        "answer": "Australia"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In which country is the Machu Picchu?",
        "answer": "Peru"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In which country would you find the Yucatan Peninsula?",
        "answer": "Mexico"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In which ocean or sea are the Seychelles?",
        "answer": "Indian Ocean"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In which state are Gettysburg and the Liberty Bell?",
        "answer": "Pennsylvania"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In which state are the Finger Lakes?",
        "answer": "New York"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In which state is Appomattax?",
        "answer": "Virginia"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In which state is Cape Hatteras?",
        "answer": "North Carolina"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In which state is Hoover Dam?",
        "answer": "Arizona"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In which state is Mount McKinley?",
        "answer": "Alaska"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In which state is Mount St. Helens?",
        "answer": "Washington"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In which state is Mount Vernon?",
        "answer": "Virginia"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In which state is Stone Mountain?",
        "answer": "Georgia"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In which state is Walla Walla?",
        "answer": "Washington"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In which state is the Kennedy Space Center?",
        "answer": "Florida"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In which state is the Mayo Clinic?",
        "answer": "Minnesota"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "In which state is the Painted Desert?",
        "answer": "Arizona"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Into what bay does the Ganges River flow?",
        "answer": "Bay Of Bengal"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Into what body of water does the Danube River flow?",
        "answer": "Black Sea"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Into what body of water does the Yukon River flow?",
        "answer": "Bering Sea"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Into what sea does the Elbe River flow?",
        "answer": "North Sea"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Into what sea does the Mackenzie River flow?",
        "answer": "Beaufort Sea"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Khartoum is the capital of which country?",
        "answer": "Sudan"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Kingston is the capital of which country?",
        "answer": "Jamaica"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Linz, Austria is a leading port on which river?",
        "answer": "Danube"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Madrid and Lisbon are both located near this river.",
        "answer": "Tagus"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Meridians converge at the --------.",
        "answer": "poles"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Mount Victoria is the highest peak of this island country.",
        "answer": "Fiji"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Name a country which has the same name as a bird.",
        "answer": "Turkey"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Name the U.S. state with the smallest population.",
        "answer": "Alaska"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Name the capital city of Massachusetts.",
        "answer": "Boston"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Name the capital city of Rhode Island.",
        "answer": "Providence"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Name the capital of Argentina.",
        "answer": "Buenos Aires"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Name the capital of Brazil.",
        "answer": "Brasilia"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Name the capital of Italy.",
        "answer": "Rome"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Name the city at the west end of Lake Superior.",
        "answer": "Duluth"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Name the continent that consists of a single country.",
        "answer": "Australia"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Name the desert located in south-east California.",
        "answer": "Mojave"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Name the large mountain chain in the eastern U.S.A.",
        "answer": "The Appalachians"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Name the largest cathedral in the world.",
        "answer": "St. Peter's"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Name the largest city in Canada.",
        "answer": "Toronto"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Name the largest island in the world.",
        "answer": "Greenland"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Name the largest lake in Australia.",
        "answer": "Eyre"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Name the largest river forming part of the U.S. - Mexican border.",
        "answer": "Rio Grande"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Name the last province to become part of Canada.",
        "answer": "Newfoundland"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Name the longest river in Asia.",
        "answer": "Yangtze"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Name the longest river in Nigeria.",
        "answer": "Niger"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Name the most north-easterly of the 48 contiguous states.",
        "answer": "Maine"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Name the only Central American country without an Atlantic coastline.",
        "answer": "El Salvador"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Name the sea between Asia Minor and Greece.",
        "answer": "Aegean"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Name the sea between Korea and China.",
        "answer": "Yellow Sea"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Name the sea north of Alaska.",
        "answer": "Beaufort"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Name the sea north of Murmansk, Russia.",
        "answer": "Barents"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Name the sea west of Alaska.",
        "answer": "Bering"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Name the second largest country in Africa.",
        "answer": "Algeria"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Name the second largest country in South America.",
        "answer": "Argentina"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Name the second largest lake in North America.",
        "answer": "Huron"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Name the smallest of the Great Lakes.",
        "answer": "Ontario"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Name the strait joining the Atlantic Ocean and the Mediterranean Sea.",
        "answer": "Gibraltar"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Name the world's most photographed and most climbed mountain.",
        "answer": "Fuji"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Nassau is the capital of which country?",
        "answer": "Bahamas"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "On what island is Honolulu?",
        "answer": "Oahu"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "On what island is Pearl Harbour?",
        "answer": "Oahu"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "On what island is the Blue Grotto?",
        "answer": "Capri"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "On what island is the U.S. naval base, Guantanamo?",
        "answer": "Cuba"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "On what mountain are four presidents' faces carved?",
        "answer": "Rushmore"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "On what peninsula are Spain and Portugal located?",
        "answer": "The Iberian peninsula"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "On what river is the capital city of Canada?",
        "answer": "Ottawa"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "On which river is London, England?",
        "answer": "Thames"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "On which river is Rome located?",
        "answer": "Tiber"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "On which river is the Aswan High Dam?",
        "answer": "Nile"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Over 75% of the Earth's surface is covered by some form of -----.",
        "answer": "Water"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Rabat is the capital of which country?",
        "answer": "Morocco"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "San Francisco Bay is located near what city?",
        "answer": "San Francisco"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Seoul is the capital of which country?",
        "answer": "South Korea"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "St. George's is the capital city of what island country?",
        "answer": "Grenada"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Surfing is believed to have originated here.",
        "answer": "Hawaii"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "The Auckland Islands belong to which country?",
        "answer": "New Zealand"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "The Hebrides are part of this country.",
        "answer": "Scotland"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "The Ionian and Cyclades are island groups of which country?",
        "answer": "Greece"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "The Little Mermaid is found in the harbour of which city?",
        "answer": "Copenhagen"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "The Nationalist Chinese occupy this island.",
        "answer": "Taiwan"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "The Thatcher Ferry Bridge crosses what canal?",
        "answer": "Panama Canal"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "The United States is made up of -- states.",
        "answer": "50"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "The Volta is the largest river in which country?",
        "answer": "Ghana"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "The countries of Belgium, Netherlands, and Luxembourg are together called --------.",
        "answer": "Benelux"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "The longest river in Western Europe is ---------?",
        "answer": "Rhine"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "The sun sets in the ----?",
        "answer": "west"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "This Canadian island is the world's fifth largest.",
        "answer": "Baffin"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "This Pacific island's puzzling monoliths attract ethnologists.",
        "answer": "Easter Island"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "This country is divided at the 38th parallel.",
        "answer": "Korea"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "This country occupies the \"horn of Africa\".",
        "answer": "Somalia"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "This country's flag has a large \"R\" on it.",
        "answer": "Rwanda"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "This imaginary line approximately follows the 180 degree meridian through the Pacific Ocean.",
        "answer": "international date line"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "This is called the \"Honeymoon Capital\" of the world.",
        "answer": "Niagara Falls"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "This is the bridge with the longest span in the U.S.A.",
        "answer": "Verrazano Narrows"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "This is the only borough of New York City that is not on an island.",
        "answer": "The Bronx"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "This is the port city serving Tokyo.",
        "answer": "Yokohama"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "This is the residence of English monarchs.",
        "answer": "Buckingham Palace"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "This island group is off the east coast of southern South America.",
        "answer": "Falkland Islands"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "This re-opened in 1975 after being closed for 8 years.",
        "answer": "Suez Canal"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "This section of Manhattan is noted for its Negro and Latin American residents.",
        "answer": "Harlem"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "To what country do the Faeroe Islands belong?",
        "answer": "Denmark"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "To what country does the Gaza Strip belong?",
        "answer": "Egypt"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "True Or False:  The Easter Bunny is from Easter Island.",
        "answer": "false"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "True Or False:  There are only virgins on the Virgin Islands.",
        "answer": "false"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Under what river does the Holland Tunnel run?",
        "answer": "Hudson"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Warsaw is the capital of what country?",
        "answer": "Poland"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What American city is known as Little Havana?",
        "answer": "Miami"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What Asian city was once called Edo?",
        "answer": "Tokyo"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What Canadian city is at the west end of Lake Ontario?",
        "answer": "Hamilton"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What European country administers the island of Martinique?",
        "answer": "France"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What European country has \"Vaduz\" as its capital city?",
        "answer": "Liechtenstein"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What London borough does the Prime Meridian pass through?",
        "answer": "Greenwich"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What U.S. city is known as Insurance City?",
        "answer": "Hartford"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What U.S. city is named after Saint Francis of Assisi?",
        "answer": "San Francisco"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What U.S. state is known as The Land of 10,000 Lakes?",
        "answer": "Minnesota"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What US state is completely surrounded by the Pacific Ocean?",
        "answer": "Hawaii"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What are drumlins and eskers formed by?",
        "answer": "glaciers"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What are the worlds four oceans - alphabetically?",
        "answer": "Arctic, Atlantic, Indian and Pacific"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What body of water borders Saudi Arabia to the east?",
        "answer": "Persian Gulf"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What canal connects Lake Ontario and Lake Erie?",
        "answer": "Welland"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What city boasts the Copacabana Beach and Ipanema?",
        "answer": "Rio de Janeiro"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What city is associated with Alcatraz?",
        "answer": "San Francisco"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What city is on Lake Erie at the mouth of the Cuyahoga River?",
        "answer": "Cleveland"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What city is the Christian Science Monitor based in?",
        "answer": "Boston"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What city is the Kremlin located in?",
        "answer": "Moscow"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What city was the setting for \"Gone With the Wind\"?",
        "answer": "Atlanta"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What color does the bride wear in China?",
        "answer": "red"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What continent is Cyprus considered to be part of?",
        "answer": "Asia"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What continent is the home to the greatest number of countries?",
        "answer": "Africa"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What country are the Islands of Quemoy and Matsu part of?",
        "answer": "Taiwan"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What country borders Egypt on the west?",
        "answer": "Libya"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What country borders Egypt to the south?",
        "answer": "Sudan"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What country does the island of Mykonos belong to?",
        "answer": "Greece"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What country formed the union of Tanganyika and Zanzibar?",
        "answer": "Tanzania"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What country has the world's most southerly city?",
        "answer": "Chile"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What country is Phnom Penh the capital of?",
        "answer": "Cambodia"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What country is Santo Domingo the capital of?",
        "answer": "Dominican Republic"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What country is directly north of Israel?",
        "answer": "Lebanon"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What country is directly north of the continental United States?",
        "answer": "Canada"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What country is directly west of Spain?",
        "answer": "Portugal"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What country is known as the Hellenic Republic?",
        "answer": "Greece"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What country is located between Panama and Nicaragua?",
        "answer": "Costa Rica"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What country owns the island of Corfu?",
        "answer": "Greece"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What country was once known as Gaul?",
        "answer": "France"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What country was the setting for \"Casablanca\"?",
        "answer": "Morocco"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What country was the setting for \"Doctor Zhivago\"?",
        "answer": "Russia"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What famous geyser erupts regularly at the Yellowstone National Park?",
        "answer": "Old Faithful"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the capital of Alaska?",
        "answer": "Juneau"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the capital of Bangladesh?",
        "answer": "Dacca"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the capital of Burma?",
        "answer": "Rangoon"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the capital of Chile?",
        "answer": "Santiago"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the capital of Colorado?",
        "answer": "Denver"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the capital of Florida?",
        "answer": "Tallahassee"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the capital of India?",
        "answer": "New Delhi"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the capital of Indonesia?",
        "answer": "Jakarta"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the capital of Kansas?",
        "answer": "Topeka"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the capital of Maine?",
        "answer": "Augusta"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the capital of Nebraska",
        "answer": "Lincoln"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the capital of New Zealand?",
        "answer": "Wellington"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the capital of Washington state?",
        "answer": "Olympia"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the capital of West Virginia?",
        "answer": "Charleston"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the capital of Wisconsin?",
        "answer": "Madison"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the capital of Zimbabwe?",
        "answer": "Harare"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the capital of the United Arab Emirates?",
        "answer": "Abu Dhabi"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the current name for south-west Africa?",
        "answer": "Namibia"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the highest mountain in Canada?",
        "answer": "Mt. Logan"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the largest city in Australia, in terms of population?",
        "answer": "Sydney"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the largest city in China?",
        "answer": "Shanghai"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the largest of the countries in Central America?",
        "answer": "Nicaragua"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the monetary unit of India?",
        "answer": "Rupee"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the most sacred river in India?",
        "answer": "Ganges"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the official language of Egypt?",
        "answer": "Arabic"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the principal river of Ireland?",
        "answer": "Shannon"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the second largest of the United States?",
        "answer": "Texas"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the smallest Canadian province?",
        "answer": "Prince Edward Island"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the smallest independent state in the world?",
        "answer": "Vatican City"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the smallest of the Central American countries?",
        "answer": "El Salvador"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What is the world's highest city?",
        "answer": "Lhasa"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What island has Hamilton as its capital?",
        "answer": "Bermuda"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What island is known as the Spice Island?",
        "answer": "Zanzibar"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What mountain range separates Europe from Asia?",
        "answer": "Ural"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What prison island was off the coast of French Guiana?",
        "answer": "Devil's Island"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What river has the largest drainage basin?",
        "answer": "Amazon"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What river is Liverpool on?",
        "answer": "Mersey"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What river is called \"Old Man River\"?",
        "answer": "Mississippi"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What river is known as China's Sorrow?",
        "answer": "Yellow"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What river is the Temple of Karnak near?",
        "answer": "Nile"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What sea is between Italy and Yugoslavia?",
        "answer": "Adriatic"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What south American country has both a Pacific and Atlantic coastline?",
        "answer": "Colombia"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What state borders Alabama to the north?",
        "answer": "Tennessee"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What state is the Golden State?",
        "answer": "California"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What state was the home to Mayberry?",
        "answer": "North Carolina"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What symbol is on the flag of Vietnam?",
        "answer": "star"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What unit of currency will buy you dinner in Iraq, Jordan, Tunisia, and Yugoslavia?",
        "answer": "Dinar"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What volcano showers ash on Sicily?",
        "answer": "Etna"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What's the former name of Istanbul?",
        "answer": "Constantinople"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "What's the highest mountain in the 48 contiguous U.S. states?",
        "answer": "Whitney"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Where are the Nazca Lines?",
        "answer": "Peru"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Where are the pyramids located?",
        "answer": "Egypt"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Where is Beacon Street?",
        "answer": "Boston"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Where is Euston Station?",
        "answer": "London"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Where is George Washington buried?",
        "answer": "Mt. Vernon, Virginia"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Where is Queen Maud Land located?",
        "answer": "Antarctica"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Where is Westminster Abbey located?",
        "answer": "London"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Where is the Admirality Arch?",
        "answer": "London"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Where is the Holy Kaaba?",
        "answer": "Mecca"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Where is the Parthenon located?",
        "answer": "Athens"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Where is the city of Brotherly Love?",
        "answer": "Philadelphia"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Where were the Pillars of Hercules located?",
        "answer": "Gibraltar"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Which Canadian province extends farthest north?",
        "answer": "Quebec"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Which Central American country extends furthest north?",
        "answer": "Belize"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Which European country has the highest population density?",
        "answer": "Monaco"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Which European country has the lowest population density?",
        "answer": "Iceland"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Which Irish city is famous for its crystal?",
        "answer": "Waterford"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Which U.S. city is known as Beantown?",
        "answer": "Boston"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Which U.S. city is known as the Biggest Little City in the World?",
        "answer": "Reno"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Which U.S. state borders a Canadian territory?",
        "answer": "Alaska"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Which U.S. state has the least rainfall?",
        "answer": "Nevada"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Which U.S. state receives the most rainfall?",
        "answer": "Hawaii"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Which capital is known as the Glass Capital of the World?",
        "answer": "Toledo"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Which city has the largest rodeo in the world?",
        "answer": "Calgary"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Which city is known as Motown?",
        "answer": "Detroit"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Which city is known as the Windy City?",
        "answer": "Chicago"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Which city is on the east side of San Francisco Bay?",
        "answer": "Oakland"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Which country administers Christmas Island?",
        "answer": "Australia"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Which country are the Galapagos Islands part of?",
        "answer": "Ecuador"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Which country borders Italy, Switzerland, West Germany, Czechoslovakia, Hungary, Yugoslavia, and Liechtenstein?",
        "answer": "Austria"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Which country developed \"Tae-Kwan-Do\"?",
        "answer": "Korea"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Which country has Ankara as its capital?",
        "answer": "Turkey"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Which country has Budapest as its capital?",
        "answer": "Hungary"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Which country has the longest land border?",
        "answer": "China"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Which country hosted the 1982 World Cup of soccer?",
        "answer": "Spain"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Which country uses the \"yen\" for currency?",
        "answer": "Japan"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Which country would come first in an alphabetical list of countries?",
        "answer": "Afghanistan"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Which islands were named after Prince Philip of Spain?",
        "answer": "The Philippines"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Which mainland Latin American country is in neither South America nor Central America?",
        "answer": "Mexico"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Which of the 48 contiguous states extends farthest north?",
        "answer": "Minnesota"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Which of the U.S. states borders only one other state?",
        "answer": "Maine"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Which river contains the most fresh water?",
        "answer": "Amazon"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Which state has the most hospitals?",
        "answer": "California"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Which state is divided into two parts by a large lake?",
        "answer": "Michigan"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Which state is the Evergreen State?",
        "answer": "Washington"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Which state is the Garden State?",
        "answer": "New Jersey"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "Which state is the Wolverine State?",
        "answer": "Michigan"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "With what country is Fidel Castro associated?",
        "answer": "Cuba"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geography",
        "question": "With which country is Prince Rainier III identified?",
        "answer": "Monaco"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geogrpahy",
        "question": "Name the capital city of Utah.",
        "answer": "Salt Lake City"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geology",
        "question": "Earth's outer layer of surface soil or crust is called the -------.",
        "answer": "Lithosphere"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geology",
        "question": "Peat, lignite and bituminous are types of ---------.",
        "answer": "coal"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geology",
        "question": "Slate is formed by the metamorphosis of ---------.",
        "answer": "shale"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geology",
        "question": "The green variety of beryl is called --------.",
        "answer": "emerald"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geology",
        "question": "The molten material from a volcano is --------?",
        "answer": "lava"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geology",
        "question": "The spot on the Earth's surface directly above an earthquake's focus is called the ------.",
        "answer": "epicenter"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geology",
        "question": "The violet variety of quartz is called --------.",
        "answer": "amethyst"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geology",
        "question": "There are three types of rocks: metamorphic, sedimentary, and ---------.",
        "answer": "igneous"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geology",
        "question": "These limestone deposits rise from the floor of caves.",
        "answer": "stalagmites"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geology",
        "question": "This is the hardest naturally occurring substance.",
        "answer": "diamond"
    },
    {
        "category": "Geology",
        "question": "What name is used to describe permanently-frozen subsoil?",
        "answer": "permafrost"
    },
    {
        "category": "Hahaha",
        "question": "This normally has 4 legs and your butt is parked in it right now.",
        "answer": "chair"
    },
    {
        "category": "Hirtory",
        "question": "Name the first black nation to gain freedom from European colonial rule.",
        "answer": "Haiti"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Britain and Argentina fought over these islands in 1982.",
        "answer": "Falklands Islands"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Canadian Prime Minister: Pierre Elliott ----------.",
        "answer": "Trudeau"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Churchill, F.D. Roosvelt and Stalin met here in 1945.",
        "answer": "Yalta"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Eras are divided into units called --------.",
        "answer": "periods"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "For what country did Columbus make his historic voyage?",
        "answer": "Spain"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Four Japanese carriers were destroyed in this battle.",
        "answer": "Midway"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Frankish ruler Charles the Great is better known as ---------.",
        "answer": "Charlemagne"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "From what country did the U.S. buy the Virgin Islands?",
        "answer": "Denmark"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "General Sherman burned this city in 1864.",
        "answer": "Atlanta"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Germany's WW I allies were Austria-Hungary, Bulgaria, and --------.",
        "answer": "Turkey"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Germany's allies in WW II were Japan, Italy, Hungary, Bulgaria, Finland, Libya, and ---------.",
        "answer": "Romania"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "He allowed the bugging of the Democratic Committee headquarters.",
        "answer": "Richard Nixon"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "He discovered the Grand Canyon.",
        "answer": "Francisco Coronado"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "He is identified with the expression, \"Eureka\".",
        "answer": "Archimedes"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "He is said to have fiddled while Rome burned.",
        "answer": "Nero"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "He led 900 followers in a mass suicide in 1979.",
        "answer": "Jim Jones"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "He ordered the persecution of Christians in which Peter and Paul died.",
        "answer": "Nero"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "He received the Nobel Peace Prize in 1964 for his civil rights leadership.",
        "answer": "Martin Luther King Jr."
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "He said, \"I have nothing to offer but blood, tears, toil and sweat.\"",
        "answer": "Sir Winston Churchill"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "He shot Lee Harvey Oswald.",
        "answer": "Jack Ruby"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "He taught Alexander the Great.",
        "answer": "Aristotle"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "He was assassinated on Dec. 8, 1980 in New York City.",
        "answer": "John Lennon"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "He was assassinated on Nov. 22, 1963.",
        "answer": "John Fitzgerald Kennedy"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "He was defeated at the Battle of Little Bighorn.",
        "answer": "General Custer"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "He was stabbed by Gaius Cassius Longinus.",
        "answer": "Julius Caesar"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "He was the American inventor of the Cotton Gin.",
        "answer": "Eli Whitney"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "He was the U.S. president during the Civil War.",
        "answer": "Abraham Lincoln"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "His ship was the H.M.S. Beagle.",
        "answer": "Charles Darwin"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "His wife was Roxana. His horse was Bacephalus. He was --------.",
        "answer": "Alexander the Great"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "How do you write 69 in Roman numerals?",
        "answer": "LXIX"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "How many astronauts manned each Apollo flight?",
        "answer": "three"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "How old was John F. Kennedy when he became president?",
        "answer": "forty three"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "In 1902 this volcano erupted, killing 30,000.",
        "answer": "Pelee"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "In what country did \"Sepoy Mutiny\" occur?",
        "answer": "India"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "In which city was President Kennedy killed?",
        "answer": "Dallas"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "In which city were the Hanging Gardens?",
        "answer": "Babylon"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "In which country did the Boxer Rebellion take place?",
        "answer": "China"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "In which country was Adolf Hitler born?",
        "answer": "Austria"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "In which country was the Rosetta Stone found?",
        "answer": "Egypt"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Israel occupied the Golan Heights.  Whose territory was it?",
        "answer": "Syria"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Israel occupied the West Bank.  It belonged to -------.",
        "answer": "Jordan"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "John F. Kennedy Airport in New York used to be called ----------.",
        "answer": "Idlewind"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Mussolini invaded this country in 1935.",
        "answer": "Ethiopia"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Name Jacques Cousteau's research ship.",
        "answer": "Calypso"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Name the incident in which tea was dumped into the harbour.",
        "answer": "Boston Tea Party"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "One who fought professionally in Roman arenas was a(n) ------------.",
        "answer": "Gladiator"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "She overcame her handicaps to become a lecturer and a scholar.",
        "answer": "Helen Keller"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "She was Queen of Egypt and mistress of Julius Caesar.",
        "answer": "Cleopatra"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "She was called \"The Maid of Orleans\".",
        "answer": "Joan of Arc"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "She was the first First Lady to be received privately by the Pope.",
        "answer": "Jackie Kennedy"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "She was the first woman premier of Israel.",
        "answer": "Golda Meir"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "She was the first woman to fly the Atlantic solo.",
        "answer": "Amelia Earhart"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "She was the first woman to swim the English channel.",
        "answer": "Gertrude Caroline Ederle"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "She was the greatest trick shot artist of all time.",
        "answer": "Annie Oakley"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "She won the 1979 Nobel Peace Prize for her work among the poor.",
        "answer": "Mother Teresa"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Spain ceded Florida to Britain in exchange for this territory.",
        "answer": "Cuba"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "The \"Bay of Pigs\" fiasco took place in this country.",
        "answer": "Cuba"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "The Devonian Period is also known as the Age of ----------.",
        "answer": "fish"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "The Inquisition forced him to recant his belief in the Copernican Theory.",
        "answer": "Galileo"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "The Romans built these to convey water.",
        "answer": "aqueducts"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "The St. Valentine's Day massacre took place in this city.",
        "answer": "Chicago"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "The first dog in space was named ---------.",
        "answer": "Laika"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "The last line of this document is \"Working men of all countries, unite.\"",
        "answer": "Communist Manifesto"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "This F.B.I agent headed the investigation of Al Capone.",
        "answer": "Elliot Ness"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "This French peasant girl led the army to victories.",
        "answer": "Joan of Arc"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "This Indian group ruled in early Peru.",
        "answer": "Inca"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "This Nazi leader had his six children poisoned prior to his own death.",
        "answer": "Joseph Goebbels"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "This Queen of France was beheaded in 1793.",
        "answer": "Marie Antoinette"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "This Roman killed himself after his defeat at Actium.",
        "answer": "Marc Antony"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "This Sioux Indian toured with Buffalo Bill's Wild West Show.",
        "answer": "Sitting Bull"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "This Spaniard conquered Mexico.",
        "answer": "Hernando Cortez"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "This U.S. Secretary of State won the Nobel Peace Prize in 1973.",
        "answer": "Henry Kissinger"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "This U.S. president was fatally shot in 1881.",
        "answer": "James Garfield"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "This assassin of Julius Caesar was his friend.",
        "answer": "Brutus"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "This frontiersman and politician was killed at the Alamo.",
        "answer": "Davy Crockett"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "This is said to be history's greatest military evacuation.",
        "answer": "Dunkirk"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "This military attack took place on Dec. 7, 1941.",
        "answer": "Pearl Harbour"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "This organization was founded by William Booth.",
        "answer": "Salvation Army"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "This racist organization was formed in Tennessee in 1865.",
        "answer": "Ku Klux Klan"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "This war began on June 25, 1950.",
        "answer": "Korean"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "This was the largest real estate deal in U.S. history.",
        "answer": "Louisiana Purchase"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "This word describes the Nazi annihilation of Jews.",
        "answer": "holocaust"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Those big black CD's that you see at garage sales that people call \"albums\" are made of -----.",
        "answer": "vinyl"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Two 747's collided here in 1977.",
        "answer": "Canary Islands"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "U.S. President, Chester Alan --------.",
        "answer": "Arthur"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "U.S. President, Herbert C. ---------.",
        "answer": "Hoover"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "U.S. President, John Quincy --------.",
        "answer": "Adams"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "U.S. President: Calvin ---------.",
        "answer": "Coolidge"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "What American feminist went bust as a silver dollar?",
        "answer": "Susan B. Anthony"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "What Chinese dynasty was overthrown in 1911?",
        "answer": "Manchu"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "What age preceded the Iron Age?",
        "answer": "The Bronze Age"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "What did President J. Buchanan not have?",
        "answer": "A wife"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "What did presidents Madison, Monroe, Polk, and Garfield have in common?",
        "answer": "The first name \"James\""
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "What group landed in America in 1620?",
        "answer": "The Pilgrims"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "What is the Roman numeral for fifty?",
        "answer": "L"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "What is the name of the Russian Czar's daughter who might-or might not-have survived the Russian revolution?",
        "answer": "Anastasia"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "What volcano destroyed Pompeii?",
        "answer": "Vesuvius"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "What was the instrument of execution during the \"Reign of Terror\"?",
        "answer": "guillotine"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "What was the name of Plato's school?",
        "answer": "Academy"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "What was the name of the B-29 used at Hiroshima to drop the bomb?",
        "answer": "Enola Gay"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "What was the nationality of the prisoners in the \"Black hole of Calcutta\"?",
        "answer": "British"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "What was the third country to get the \"bomb\"?",
        "answer": "Britain"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "What's the resting place of those buried at sea?",
        "answer": "Davey Jones's Locker"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Which U.S. president said, \"The buck stops here\"?",
        "answer": "Truman"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Which military battle took place in 1815?",
        "answer": "Waterloo"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Which nation was led by Genghis Khan?",
        "answer": "The Mongols"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Which president was responsible for the Louisiana Purchase?",
        "answer": "Jefferson"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Who is \"The Iron Lady\"?",
        "answer": "Margaret Thatcher"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Who led the attack on the Alamo?",
        "answer": "Santa Ana"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Who rode naked through the streets of Coventry?",
        "answer": "Lady Godiva"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Who said \"Veni, vidi, vici\" (I came, I saw, I conquered)?",
        "answer": "Julius Caesar"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Who said: \"Let them eat cake\"?",
        "answer": "Marie Antoinette"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Who sang Happy Birthday to John F. Kennedy for his 45th?",
        "answer": "Marilyn Monroe"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Who succeeded Churchill when he resigned in 1955?",
        "answer": "Sir Anthony Eden"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Who was \"The Mad Monk\"?",
        "answer": "Rasputin"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Who was George Washington's vice-president?",
        "answer": "Adams"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Who was the first chancellor of West Germany after WW II?",
        "answer": "Konrad Adenauer"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Who was the second man to set foot on the moon?",
        "answer": "Edwin \"Buzz\" Aldrin"
    },
    {
        "category": "History",
        "question": "Who was, \"First in war, first in peace and first in the hearts of his countrymen\"?",
        "answer": "George Washington"
    },
    {
        "category": "IRC",
        "question": "What three letters are overly used to indicate \"Laugh Out Loud\"?",
        "answer": "lol"
    },
    {
        "category": "Langauge",
        "question": "Many Meanings:  Fuel, vapor, flattulence, helium.  What is it?",
        "answer": "gas"
    },
    {
        "category": "Language",
        "question": "Multiple Meanings:  Drinking utensils or sight-enhancers.",
        "answer": "glasses"
    },
    {
        "category": "Language",
        "question": "Multiple Meanings:  Slamming your hands together quickly, or a venereal disease.",
        "answer": "clap"
    },
    {
        "category": "Language",
        "question": "Name the soda that is often confused with a drug.",
        "answer": "Coke"
    },
    {
        "category": "Language",
        "question": "Subject, verb and object are parts of a ---------.",
        "answer": "sentence"
    },
    {
        "category": "Language",
        "question": "This animal is found at the beginning of an (English) encyclopedia",
        "answer": "aardvark"
    },
    {
        "category": "Language",
        "question": "What is the only English word formed by the first three letters of the alphabet?",
        "answer": "cab"
    },
    {
        "category": "Language",
        "question": "What three letter word means the same as \"to ingest\"?",
        "answer": "eat"
    },
    {
        "category": "Languages",
        "question": "\"faux pas\" means -----------.",
        "answer": "mistake"
    },
    {
        "category": "Languages",
        "question": "Mardi Gras is French for -----------.",
        "answer": "fat tuesday"
    },
    {
        "category": "Languages",
        "question": "The name Australia is derived from the Latin word \"australis\" which means -------.",
        "answer": "southern"
    },
    {
        "category": "Languages",
        "question": "The name for this semi-precious stone comes from the Latin for \"sea water\"",
        "answer": "aquamarine"
    },
    {
        "category": "Languages",
        "question": "What ONE word fits? ----hood; ----hole; ----date.",
        "answer": "man"
    },
    {
        "category": "Languages",
        "question": "What ONE word fits? ----stream; ----hill; -----pour.",
        "answer": "down"
    },
    {
        "category": "Languages",
        "question": "What does \"c'est la vie\" mean?",
        "answer": "that's life"
    },
    {
        "category": "Languages",
        "question": "What word contains the combination of letters: \"xop\"?",
        "answer": "saXOPhone"
    },
    {
        "category": "Literature",
        "question": "\"The Diary of Anne Frank\" was first published in English under what title?",
        "answer": "The Diary of a Young Girl"
    },
    {
        "category": "Literature",
        "question": "Captain Hook, Tiger Lily, and Tinker Bell are characters in what story?",
        "answer": "Peter Pan"
    },
    {
        "category": "Literature",
        "question": "Dr. Seuss wrote this book: The Cat in the ------.",
        "answer": "Hat"
    },
    {
        "category": "Literature",
        "question": "Edgar Allen Poe wrote a famous poem about this animal.",
        "answer": "raven"
    },
    {
        "category": "Literature",
        "question": "From which Shakespeare play is this line taken: \"Double, double ... \"",
        "answer": "Macbeth"
    },
    {
        "category": "Literature",
        "question": "From which Shakespeare play is this line taken: \"Goodnight, goodnight! Parting is such sweet sorrow, That I should say goodnight till it be morrow.\"",
        "answer": "Romeo and Juliet"
    },
    {
        "category": "Literature",
        "question": "From which Shakespeare play is this line taken: \"To be or not to be?\"",
        "answer": "Hamlet"
    },
    {
        "category": "Literature",
        "question": "From which Shakespeare play is this line taken: \"What in a name? That which we call a rose, by any other name would smell as sweet.\"",
        "answer": "Romeo and Juliet"
    },
    {
        "category": "Literature",
        "question": "How many lines are in a sonnet?",
        "answer": "fourteen"
    },
    {
        "category": "Literature",
        "question": "How many plays is Shakespeare generally credited with today?",
        "answer": "thirty seven"
    },
    {
        "category": "Literature",
        "question": "Name the Shakespeare play from this ultra short plot summary: Urged on by his wife, a man murders his king in order to take his place.",
        "answer": "Macbeth"
    },
    {
        "category": "Literature",
        "question": "Stephen King's: \"Pet --------\".",
        "answer": "Semetary"
    },
    {
        "category": "Literature",
        "question": "Stephen King's: \"Salem's ---------\".",
        "answer": "Lot"
    },
    {
        "category": "Literature",
        "question": "Stephen King's: \"The Dead --------\".",
        "answer": "Zone"
    },
    {
        "category": "Literature",
        "question": "This Shakespearean king was the actual king of Scotland for 17 years.",
        "answer": "Macbeth"
    },
    {
        "category": "Literature",
        "question": "This girl hid from the Nazis in Amsterdam.",
        "answer": "Anne Frank"
    },
    {
        "category": "Literature",
        "question": "What Shakespearean play features the line: A plague on both your houses?",
        "answer": "Romeo and Juliet"
    },
    {
        "category": "Literature",
        "question": "What did Jeannie C. Riley describe as \"a little Peyton Place\"?",
        "answer": "Harper Valley"
    },
    {
        "category": "Literature",
        "question": "What other name does Stephen King write under?",
        "answer": "Richard Bachman"
    },
    {
        "category": "Literature",
        "question": "What publication was subtitled The What's New Magazine?",
        "answer": "Popular Science"
    },
    {
        "category": "Literature",
        "question": "What was the name of Mother Goose's son?",
        "answer": "Jack"
    },
    {
        "category": "Literature",
        "question": "What's Penthouse's sister publication for women?",
        "answer": "Viva"
    },
    {
        "category": "Litterature",
        "question": "Homer wrote this account of the Trojan War.",
        "answer": "Iliad"
    },
    {
        "category": "Logic",
        "question": "You are in a room where all walls face south.  A bear walks by.  What color is it?",
        "answer": "White"
    },
    {
        "category": "Mathematics",
        "question": "A U.S. dime is worth --- cents.",
        "answer": "ten"
    },
    {
        "category": "Mathematics",
        "question": "A line drawn from an angle of a triangle to the mid-point of the opposite side is a(n) -------.",
        "answer": "median"
    },
    {
        "category": "Mathematics",
        "question": "A triangle with three equal sides is called -------.",
        "answer": "equilateral"
    },
    {
        "category": "Mathematics",
        "question": "A triangle with two equal sides is called ----------.",
        "answer": "isosceles"
    },
    {
        "category": "Mathematics",
        "question": "An angle greater than 180 degrees and less than 360 degrees is a(n) -------- angle.",
        "answer": "reflex"
    },
    {
        "category": "Mathematics",
        "question": "An angle greater than 90 degrees and less than 180 degrees is said to be ---------.",
        "answer": "obtuse"
    },
    {
        "category": "Mathematics",
        "question": "An integer that is greater than 1 and is divisible only by itself and 1 is known as a(n) -------.",
        "answer": "prime"
    },
    {
        "category": "Mathematics",
        "question": "Approximately how many inches are there in one meter?",
        "answer": "thirty nine"
    },
    {
        "category": "Mathematics",
        "question": "Arc, radius, and sector are parts of a(n) ---------.",
        "answer": "circle"
    },
    {
        "category": "Mathematics",
        "question": "He is known as \"The Father of Geometry\".",
        "answer": "Euclid"
    },
    {
        "category": "Mathematics",
        "question": "How many corners are there in a cube?",
        "answer": "eight"
    },
    {
        "category": "Mathematics",
        "question": "How many nickles are there in 2.25?",
        "answer": "forty five"
    },
    {
        "category": "Mathematics",
        "question": "If you cut through a solid sphere what shape will the flat area be?",
        "answer": "circle"
    },
    {
        "category": "Mathematics",
        "question": "Name the number system which uses only the symbols 1 and 0.",
        "answer": "The binary system"
    },
    {
        "category": "Mathematics",
        "question": "The angles inside a square total ------- degrees.",
        "answer": "three hundred and sixty"
    },
    {
        "category": "Mathematics",
        "question": "The mathematical study of properties of lines, angels, etc., is --------.",
        "answer": "geometry"
    },
    {
        "category": "Mathematics",
        "question": "The space occupied by a body is called its ------.",
        "answer": "volume"
    },
    {
        "category": "Mathematics",
        "question": "The square root of 1 is?",
        "answer": "1"
    },
    {
        "category": "Mathematics",
        "question": "Two angles that total 180 degrees are called -------.",
        "answer": "supplementary"
    },
    {
        "category": "Mathematics",
        "question": "What geometric shape has 4 equal sides?",
        "answer": "square"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "A baby doctor is a ---------.",
        "answer": "pediatrician"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "A bone specialist is a(n) --------.",
        "answer": "osteopath"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "A loss of memory is known as ----------.",
        "answer": "amnesia"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "A medicine that hastens the emptying of the bowels is called a --------.",
        "answer": "laxative"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "A non-cancerous tumor is said to be -------.",
        "answer": "benign"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "A thread used in surgery to tie a bleeding blood vessel is called a(n) ---------.",
        "answer": "ligature"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "Carditis, affects the --------.",
        "answer": "heart"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "Doctors often have this instrument around their neck.",
        "answer": "stethoscope"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "Due to a lack of vitamin C, sailors used to contract this disease.",
        "answer": "scurvy"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "Encephalitis affects the --------.",
        "answer": "brain"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "Gastritis affects the ----------.",
        "answer": "stomach"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "Hammer, anvil, and stirrup are parts of the --------.",
        "answer": "ear"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "He discovered the process of vaccination for prevention of smallpox.",
        "answer": "Edward Jenner"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "Hepatitis affects the ----------.",
        "answer": "Liver"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "How many bones are there in the human body?",
        "answer": "two hundred and six"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "How many chambers does the human heart have?",
        "answer": "four"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "How many pints of blood does the average human have in his/her body?",
        "answer": "twelve"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "In the field of psychiatry this term means self-love.",
        "answer": "narcissism"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "In what organ of the body is insulin produced?",
        "answer": "pancreas"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "In which organ is a clear watery solution known as the \"aqueous humor\" found?",
        "answer": "eye"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "In which organ is a pulmonary disease located?",
        "answer": "lung"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "In which organ is your \"hypothalmus\" located?",
        "answer": "brain"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "Infantile Paralysis is commonly known as --------.",
        "answer": "polio"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "Meningitis affects the ---------.",
        "answer": "brain"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "Myositis affects the ---------.",
        "answer": "muscles"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "Name the hardest substance in the human body.",
        "answer": "enamel"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "Name the largest artery in the human body.",
        "answer": "aorta"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "Name the largest gland in the human body.",
        "answer": "liver"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "Osteomyelitis affects the ---------.",
        "answer": "bones"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "Peritonitis, affects the --------.",
        "answer": "abdomen"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "Prosthetics deals with the making of ----------.",
        "answer": "artificial limbs"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "Tarsus, metatarsus, and phalanges are parts of a(n) ---------.",
        "answer": "foot"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "The branch of medicine dealing with curing by operative procedures is --------.",
        "answer": "surgery"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "The lack of this element in the diet is a cause of goitre.",
        "answer": "iodine"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "The largest single organ of the human body is the --------.",
        "answer": "skin"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "The medical name for the voice box is the ---------.",
        "answer": "larynx"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "The teeth used for biting or cutting are known as -------.",
        "answer": "incisors"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "These animals were once used to bleed the sick.",
        "answer": "leeches"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "These attach muscles to bones or cartilage.",
        "answer": "tendons"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "This branch of medicine deals with old age and its diseases.",
        "answer": "geriatrics"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "This disease consists of a purposeless, continual growth of white blood cells.",
        "answer": "leukemia"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "This fingerlike projection is attached to the large intestine.",
        "answer": "appendix"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "This is known as \"The Royal Disease\".",
        "answer": "haemophilia"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "This large bean-shaped lymph gland can expand and contract as needed.",
        "answer": "spleen"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "This membrane controls the amount of light entering the eye.",
        "answer": "iris"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "This organ is a small pouch that stores bile.",
        "answer": "gall bladder"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "This parasite lives in the intestines of man and animals.",
        "answer": "tapeworm"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "This small gland attached to the brain exerts a control over growth.",
        "answer": "pituitary"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "Ulna, radius, and clavicle are types of ----------.",
        "answer": "bone"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "What disease is also known as \"rubella\"?",
        "answer": "German measles"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "What hormone is produced by the adrenal glands?",
        "answer": "adrenaline"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "What is a skin specialist called?",
        "answer": "dermatologist"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "What is an organism called that lives on or in a host animal?",
        "answer": "parasite"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "What is the biggest disqualifying factor for prospective astronauts?",
        "answer": "eyesight"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "What is the medical term for cancer of the blood?",
        "answer": "leukemia"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "What is the name of the bone in the lower leg?",
        "answer": "tibia"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "What kind of poisoning is known as plumbism?",
        "answer": "lead poisoning"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "What toe is the foot reflexology pressure point for the head?",
        "answer": "big toe"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "Where do you find the medulla oblongata?",
        "answer": "brain"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "Where in the body is the tiniest human muscle?",
        "answer": "ear"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "Which disease is also known as \"Hansen's Disease\"?",
        "answer": "leprosy"
    },
    {
        "category": "Medicine",
        "question": "With what body part is otology involved?",
        "answer": "ear"
    },
    {
        "category": "Meteorology",
        "question": "If the groundhog sees his shadow on Feb. 2, there will be how many more weeks of bad weather?",
        "answer": "six"
    },
    {
        "category": "Meteorology",
        "question": "This dry, warm wind flows eastward down the slopes of the Rocky Mountains.",
        "answer": "Chinook"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Actor: ------- Borgnine.",
        "answer": "Ernest"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Actor: -------- Hackman.",
        "answer": "Gene"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Actor: ---------- Nimoy.",
        "answer": "Leonard"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Actor: ---------- Savalas.",
        "answer": "Telly"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "At the end of \"Planet of the Apes\" what protruded from the rocks?",
        "answer": "Statue of Liberty"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Barbara Streisand was the female lead in \"Hello, Dolly\".  Who was the male lead?",
        "answer": "Walter Matthau"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Charles Laughton played Quasimodo in this epic film.",
        "answer": "Hunchback of Notre Dame"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Darth Vader was the villan in the movie, \"---- Wars\".",
        "answer": "Star"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Film Title: An Officer and a(n) ---------.",
        "answer": "Gentleman"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Film Title: Fahrenheit --------. (a number)",
        "answer": "451"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Film Title: The Last Days of ---------. (a city)",
        "answer": "Pompeii"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Film Title: ------ (a number) Leagues Under the Sea.",
        "answer": "20,000"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Forrest ---- liked shrimp.",
        "answer": "Gump"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "He directed \"The Godfather\".",
        "answer": "Francis Ford Coppola"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "He directed the movie E.T.",
        "answer": "Stephen Spielberg"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "He played Superman in the 1978 movie version.",
        "answer": "Christopher Reeve"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "He starred in \"Conan the Barbarian\".",
        "answer": "Arnold Schwarzenegger"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "He starred in, \"City Lights\".",
        "answer": "Charlie Chaplin"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "He was known as the \"Elephant Man\".",
        "answer": "Joseph Merrick"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "He was the villain in \"Star Wars\".",
        "answer": "Darth Vader"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "His films include: Giant, Written on the Wind, and A Farewell to Arms.",
        "answer": "Rock Hudson"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "His films include: Spartacus, The Vikings, and Ulysses.",
        "answer": "Kirk Douglas"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "In \"Gone With the Wind\", Scarlett regains her wealth by investing in what type of business?",
        "answer": "sawmill"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "In 1975 Jack Nicholson won the best actor Oscar for his role in this film.",
        "answer": "One Flew Over the Cuckoo's Nest"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "In the 1996 version of \"Romeo and Juliet\", who played Juliet?",
        "answer": "Claire Danes"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "In the film \"Bright Eyes\", Shirley Temple sang about this boat.",
        "answer": "The Good Ship Lollipop"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "In this 1968 film the husband of an unsuspecting young wife becomes involved with a witch's coven.",
        "answer": "Rosemary's Baby"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "In which Disney movie is the song \"So This Is Love\"?",
        "answer": "Cinderella"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Name the Disney cartoon in which the character \"Belle\" appears.",
        "answer": "Beauty and the Beast"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Name the actor who played the leading role in \"The Good, the Bad, and the Ugly\".",
        "answer": "Clint Eastwood"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Name the first full length color cartoon talking picture.",
        "answer": "Snow White"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Name the musical film named after a state.",
        "answer": "Oklahoma"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Nick Nolte and Eddie Murphy star in this 1982 film.",
        "answer": "48 Hours"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "Peter Sellers is best known for his role as Inspector ---------.",
        "answer": "Clouseau"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "She played Lois Lane in the 1978 film version of \"Superman\".",
        "answer": "Margot Kidder"
    },
    {
        "category": "Movie Trivia",
        "question": "She played a Polish refugee in \"Sophie's Choice\".",
        "answer": "Meryl Streep"
    }
]
